hey everybody welcome to this b1
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram you ready so
today
i'm going to talk about immigration this
is a really relevant topic for today
because as the world becomes more
globalized
immigration becomes more common nowadays
more and more people
are considering immigrating abroad for
different reasons
some people leave the country looking
for a better job some people are looking
for a safer environment
and some simply want a change of scenery
all in all there are a plethora of
reasons one might choose to immigrate
i personally have lived abroad for
almost four years and so
i too have had a lot of experience with
immigration
so let's talk about the pros of
immigrating to another country
and then we'll talk about the cons as
well so the first positive that comes to
mind
is the cultural experience forcing
yourself out of your comfort zone can
always bring benefits
regardless of how difficult it is for
you before i moved abroad i
still hadn't broken out of my shell so
to say but once i started my life in a
foreign country
my horizons expanded i made new friends
i tried new activities and i spoke a new
language
granted it's not easy to make all these
changes but it's such a great learning
experience
you discover all kinds of new things
along the way especially about yourself
you realize what things about your life
you really value
and what things you're willing to change
okay another positive about immigrating
to a new country
is that it can sometimes provide you
with more career opportunities
i've had tons of students who moved
abroad because they have the opportunity
to grow in their career
and earn more money to support their
family in some countries
salaries are low or the currency isn't
strong
and so it might make sense economically
for people to move somewhere else
one last positive thing about
immigrating is that it gives you a
chance to learn a new language
when you're forced to speak a foreign
language to do all the things that you
need to do
you learn a lot faster it's definitely
stressful but it could be that last
piece of the puzzle that you need in
order to master a language
for example my spanish improved a ton
after i moved to mexico
alright now let's talk about some cons
of moving abroad
the absolute worst thing about
immigrating is that you're probably
leaving loved ones behind
no matter how exciting it is for you to
live in your new country
you can't help but miss your family and
friends back home
sure you can call them or video chat
with them but it's no substitute for
actually being with them in the flesh
it might get easier over time but you'll
never stop missing your loved ones
another negative about moving abroad is
culture shock
i already talked about the positives
that can come from exposing yourself to
another culture
but sometimes it's not that great
regardless of how interested you are in
a foreign culture
you'll never adopt 100 of their values
and norms
heck we don't even agree with a hundred
percent of our own culture's values
culture shock is inevitable when you
move abroad because you have so many
opportunities for misunderstandings
miscommunications and exposure to
foreign ideas i've experienced my share
of culture shock throughout my time
abroad
it's something that you simply have to
expect when you put yourself in this
sort of situation
one last negative about immigrating is
that you might lose your sense of where
home is
after you spend a significant time
abroad you might start to realize that
you don't really know where you consider
your home to be
of course if you just spend a year
abroad you'll probably come back home
afterwards and adapt without issue
but if you live abroad for multiple
years you might find that when you
return back to your home country
you experience reverse culture shock the
things that used to be normal for you
are now foreign weird huh okay now i'm
going to ask you
three questions about today's video to
check your comprehension
write your answers in a comment down
below number one
how long have i lived abroad for number
two
what do i consider the worst thing about
moving abroad
and number three what might happen to
you if you return home
after having lived abroad for many years
alright before we go
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram for more
english tips and lessons
i'll see you next time
you